Animation Number 1
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'll take it, Senjougahara.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（貝木(かいき)）
引き受けよう
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Take it?
（戦場ヶ原）引き受けるって
Take what?
何をよ？
Your request. What else is there?
（貝木）
お前の依頼をだ　ほかに何がある
Deceiving a god? I'll take a shot at it.
神様だまし
やってやろうじゃないか
Are you sane?
正気？
I am sane.
正気だ
For now, give me the 100,000 yen that you said you could pay immediately.
とりあえず 即金で払えるという
10万円をよこせ
All right. This will be good enough.
いいだろう　この額でいい
No, that's only a down payment. What you might call earnest money...
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ それは あくまで前金
手付けであって…
I'm telling you, this will be good enough.
これでいいと言っているんだ
If I invoiced you for what I really feel is fitting for the job...
俺が本気で
仕事に見合うだけの額を請求すれば
...you selling yourself wouldn't be enough.
お前が身売りをしても足りんよ
No matter how harsh the work, it wouldn't be enough.
どんな過酷に働いても足りん
I only accepted this 100,000 yen to pay for necessary expenses.
この10万円も あくまで
必要経費として受け取っただけだ
でも それは　それは…
But, that's... That's....
It's justified caution.
Animation Number 25
If I end up not using all of the money and have some left over, I won't be that nit-picky.
（貝木）
もしも 使いきれずに余ったら
そこまで俺も細かいことは言うまい
I'll gladly accept the change.
その分くらいは受け取ってやろう
この条件以外では俺は引き受けない
That is the only condition with which I'll take this job.
Gate              Remarks  Change   Sched                       Dest                   Flight
22                                               Boarding                                  13:15 Ishigaki                      601
28                                               Departing soon                        13:15 Osaka/Kansai            270
20                                               Boarding                                  13:25 Miyako                       551
24                                               Bus transfer                             13:35 Kume                         871
21                                               Boarding                                  13:50 Fukuoka                     050
31                                               Boarding                                   15:15 Tokyo                         900
27                                               Boarding                                  15:45 Ishigaki
33                                               Bus transfer                             16:05 Miyako                       801
25                                               Bus transfer                             16:15 Yonaguni                   721
23                                               Boarding                                   16:25 Tokyo                         120
26                                               Boarding                                   16:35
All right.
分かったわ
Curry fair
Curry bread
Freshly fried curry bread
Then, let me get into the details.
じゃあ
詳しい話をさせてもらおうかしら
Are you sure that you only have 74 days left?
残りの日数が74日というのは
間違いないのか？
Yes. The graduation ceremony for Naoetsu High is on March 15th.
ええ　直江津(なおえつ)高校の卒業式は
３月15日よ
その日の午後 つまり卒業式のあと
打ち上げをすることも許されずに
That afternoon, in other words, after the graduation ceremony...
...without being able to finish my school days with a party...
私と阿良々木(あららぎ)くん それに忍野(おしの) 忍(しのぶ)は
殺されることになっている
...myself, Araragi-kun, and Oshino Shinobu are going to be killed.
Is that absolute? Are you absolutely sure?
絶対か？
絶対に確かか？
For instance, can this god lose her temper and kill you today? At this moment?
例えば神様が短気を起こして
今日の この瞬間にも お前が
殺されるということは ないのか？
No, I don't think so.
（戦場ヶ原）ないと思う
Why?
（貝木）どうして？
To put this directly, you, and probably Araragi as well, are planning...
極端な話 お前は そして多分
阿良々木もだろうが
...a way for you guys to stay alive, whether it be consulting me or something else, right?
こうして俺に相談するなり何なり
自分たちが生き残るための
策を練っているのだろう？
That should be an act that hideously ruins this god's impression of you.
それは神様の心証を
著しく害する行為のはずだ
向こうが怒って
You can't just deny the possibility
期限よりも早く お前たちを
始末しにかかるという可能性は
that she'll get mad and get rid of you guys earlier than the deadline.
どうしたって
否定しきれないはずだろう
Just because she's a god, it doesn't mean she keeps her promise for sure.
Animation Number 59
I can deny it.
否定できるわ
否定できるのよ
I can deny it. Because Nadeko is as angry as she can ever be at this point.
だって千石撫子(せんごくなでこ)は もう
これ以上なく怒っているんだもの
Faithful land
現時点で
Yet, Araragi-kun and I are still alive.
それなのに
まだ私や阿良々木くんは生きている
ということは約束を守る気くらいは
あるということよ
Which means she intends on keeping her promise.
You... You guys... What kind of grudge did you buy from this Sengoku Nadeko?
（貝木）お前 お前たち
一体 その千石撫子から
どんな恨みを買ったんだ？
What in the world did you do to put you at risk of getting killed?
一体 何をして
殺されるところまで いったんだ？
That's...
それは…
...something I don't know.
分からないわ
Come on, there's no way you don't know!
（貝木）
おいおい
分からないってことがあるか？
But I really don't know.
（戦場ヶ原）
それが本当に分からないのよ
No, of course... How do you put it...
いえ もちろん 何ていうか
原因めいたことや失敗や行き違いや
勘違いや間違いは あるのだけれど
There are things like a cause, an error, a disagreement, a misunderstanding, a mistake...
But that's all, and I really don't know why things ended up the way they did.
ただそれだけで 本当に
こんなことに なるのかどうかが
分からないっていうか…
I feel like there's another side to this that's vastly different from how Araragi-kun and I see this.
私や阿良々木くんがしている
理解とは全然違う裏側が
そこには ありそうなの
Though, I'm just believing what Hanekawa-san said.
この辺の言葉は
羽川(はねかわ)さんの受け売りなのだけれど
This Hanekawa again?
（貝木）
また羽川か
But for now, I'll say whatever needs to be said as a starter. Just regard this...
（戦場ヶ原）
それでも一応 とっかかりとして
言うだけのことは言っておくけれど
...as a romantic entanglement gone wrong.
恋愛関係のもつれだと思っておいて
Welcome to Okinawa!  Welcome to Okinawa!  Welcome to Okinawa!  Welcome to Okinawa!
Before she became a god, Nadeko was in love with Araragi-kun, but he had a girlfriend...
千石撫子は神様になる前
阿良々木くんのことが好きで
Wanna swim? Then Okinawa!          Wanna swim? Then Okinawa!          Wanna swim? Then Okinawa!           Wanna swim? Then Okinawa!
Okinawa
First dip                       First dip                      First dip                       First dip
First time                              First time                              First time                             First time
だけど阿良々木くんには
彼女がいて…
That kind of thing.
みたいな話
It's that lowbrow a tale?
低俗な話だな
Well, all right. I think hearing that much should be enough.
まあ いいだろう
それだけ聞けば十分だ
But, I'm assuming that this case is an exception?
しかし 今回は例外ということで
いいんだろうな？
（戦場ヶ原）ん？　例外って何？
Exception to what?
I mean, it's all right for me to go back to your town.
（貝木）だから
お前たちの町に入って
いいんだろうなということだ
Of course. That's a given.
（戦場ヶ原）
それは もちろん当たり前よ
This case is an exception, or rather, something special, so do as you please.
今回のケースは例外
というか特別だと思って
自由に振る舞ってちょうだい
But be careful.
でも 気をつけてよ
There are people out there that hold a grudge against you.
あなたに恨みを持つ人間は
少なからずいるわ
Please make sure that you don't...
中学生にボコボコにされて
身元不明の遺体として発見される
...get beaten to a pulp by a junior high kid, only to be left as an unidentifiable corpse.
なんてことは ないようにしてね
This girl says scary stuff.
Animation Number 85
Getting warned like this
makes me want to stay away.
Animation Number 85
And this is a given, but please make sure Araragi-kun doesn't see you either.
当然だけれど 阿良々木くんにも
見つからないようにしてちょうだい
Hmph... Fair enough. Well, I don't want to see him either.
（貝木）
ふん そうだな
まあ俺もヤツには会いたくない
よ〜し分かった
All right.
I'll start the investigation today, immediately.
今日から すぐに
調査に取りかかることにしよう
That said, Senjougahara, don't think that this will be solved in a day or two.
そうは言っても 戦場ヶ原
１日２日で解決すると思うなよ
Yes. I'm prepared for this to be a long fight. Or rather, it's already a long fight to begin with.
長期戦は覚悟しているわ
ていうか 既に長期戦だし
でも連絡は
こまめに取らせてもらうわよ
But I'm going to contact you often.
仕事を依頼しておいて
なんだけれど
This feels strange after requesting services from you,
あなたを全面的に信用するのは
私には不可能なの
but it's impossible for me to completely trust you.
それでいい　信じるな 疑え
That's how it should be.
Don't trust. Doubt.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Check-in
I'm going to head into your town before the end of today by airplane...
飛行機で今日中にお前たちの町まで
乗り込むわけだが
...but I figure we should take different flights.
便は お前と別のものに
しておいたほうがいいだろうな
Buy a Ryuukyuu Beauty as your souvenir!
Ryuukyuu Beauty
Super Popular
Charm
It would be no joke if Araragi ever finds out that I was on the same airplane as you were.
お前と一緒に飛行機に乗っていた
という事実を
阿良々木にでも知られては
本当に しゃれにならない
Yes, true.
（戦場ヶ原）ええ そうね
By the way, Kaiki...
ところで 貝木
What?
何だ？
Well, can you lend me money so I can buy my flight home?
その…
帰りの飛行機代を
貸していただけないかしら
Hitagi End          Part Two
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Animation Number 108
Emergency Exit
I'm here.
（貝木）着いたぞ
Thank you. I'm counting on you.
（戦場ヶ原）
ありがとう　よろしく
Unknown Name
Yeah.
Animation Number 124
2nd of January
Soon after 10 AM,
Animation Number 128
I
went into town.
Animation Number 128
Kaguya
Good Luck
Improved Luck
Improved
Luck
Treasure
New
year
Big
sale
New
year
Big
sale
Happy New Year
New Year's sale
Next train
10:55  Hanamaru   Local   Next
11:12  Circle Square Triangle Express
10:45  Naoetsu   Local   Next
10:58  Double Square   Local
Animation Number 152
I decided to start this case by heading directly into the central location.
（貝木）
俺は まず いきなり本丸から
この件に切り込むことにした
Where is the central location for this case?
この件の本丸とは どこか
Labor
Credit
Union
Town of fulfilling life and work
Trendy and Stylish
Great Selection
Japanese Gourmet
Kusa-Chiyo
BBQ
Marutori
Kaku Bookstore
3rd floor
Books
One is definitely North Shirahebi Shrine.
１つは北白蛇(きたしらへび)神社だろう
1 2 3
First stop
Second stop
Third stop
But going there as the very first location is past reckless and outright foolish.
しかし さすがに のっけから
そこに乗り込むのは
無謀を通り越して愚かである
Which means the other central location should be visited first.
とすると もう１つの本丸だ
そちらが先だ
It feels weird that there are multiple locations...
本丸が２つも３つもあるのは
おかしい気もするが
...to be tagged as central locations, but the other central location is Sengoku Nadeko's house.
ともかく もう１つの本丸とは
千石撫子の家である
Unknown Name
What is it? Are there new developments or something?
（戦場ヶ原）
何よ？　何か進展があったの？
I've just finished my preparations. I'm going to start acting now.
（貝木）
準備が終わったところだ
これから行動に移る
It seems pretty rowdy behind you. Where are you this early in the year?
なんだか後ろが騒がしいな
三が日からお前 どこにいるんだ？
Araragi-kun's house.
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くんの家よ
Senjougahara replied.
Animation Number 150
Though she didn't have to.
I got an invitation over. My father's here too.
ちょっと招待されてね
お父さんもいて
Well, so it's like our families get along with each other.
まあ 家族ぐるみの
おつきあいというか
How heartwarming.
ほほえましいことだな
Don't put it that way.
Long
life
（戦場ヶ原）
言わないでよ そういうふうに
I already know how easygoing and comical all of what we are doing sounds...
自分たちが どんなのんきで
滑稽なことをしているかなんて
分かっているんだから
I want to know Sengoku Nadeko's address. Text it to me.
千石撫子の住所が知りたい
携帯メールで教えてくれ
Animation Number 185
Sengoku Residence
I posed as the father of one of Sengoku Nadeko's classmates...
（貝木）
俺は 千石撫子の
同級生の父親を名乗って
Sengoku
...in other words, I deceived my way into the Sengoku household.
つまりは 騙(かた)って
千石ハウスの中に入った
"My daughter has been missing for the last three days as well."
“うちの娘も３日前から
いなくなってしまったんです”
"I think she mentioned something about your daughter right before she disappeared."
“直前に何か”
“お宅のお嬢さんのことを
言っていたような気がするので”
"That's been on my mind, so I'm here, knowing that it's pretty thoughtless of me."
“それが気がかりで 非常識にも
押しかけてしまいました”
"Would you like to tell me a few things about your daughter?" And so on.
“お嬢さんの話を”
“聞かせていただいても
よろしいでしょうか？” うんぬん
As soon as I said their daughter's name "Nadeko-san"...
娘の撫子さんの名前を出したら
両親は見知らぬ来客に対する
警戒心を完全に失ってしまった
...the parents completely dropped all alarm at the strange visitor.
However, the Sengoku couple knew not of their daughter. Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
だが千石夫妻は娘のことを一切
一切合財 何も知らなかった
Someone afraid of strangers. A well-behaved girl. A girl that laughed a lot.
人見知りだったとか
おとなしい子だったとか
よく笑う子だったとか
I think they were talking about things like that.
そんなことを
言っていたような気もするが
But, what I wanted to know weren't such words of a loving parent...
俺が知りたいのは そんな
子ぼんのうのセリフではなく
...but the shadows she harbored in her heart.
彼女の抱える心の闇だったのだが
They didn't seem know of such a thing, and furthermore, didn't want to ever find out about it.
そんなものは彼らも知らないらしく
しかも知りたくもないようだった
And so I asked them, "Would it be all right if I could take a look at her room?"
そして俺は
“娘さんの部屋を見せてもらっても
かまわないでしょうか”
と言った
I started with "I believe my daughter lent something to Nadeko-san...
“娘が撫子さんに貸していた
なになにがあるはずで”
...and that may be a clue to finding their whereabouts. Would you have any ideas?"
“それが２人を捜すうえでの
手がかりになるはずなのですが”
Then I beat around the bush for 30 minutes or so and finally arrived at that goal.
“心当たりは
ございませんでしょうか”
というところから始めて
30分ぐらい遠回りをしたあげくに
ようやく
そのゴールまで たどりついたのだ
Nadeko's room
Animation Number 240
I thought, if anything...
子供っぽさや かわいらしさを
無理やり押しつけられているような
部屋だというふうに
...the room was one where immaturity and cuteness were being forced against her will.
むしろ俺は思った
Combine that with how Nadeko's father said something about her never rebelling against him...
先ほど千石撫子の父親が
娘には反抗期がなかった
というようなことを言っていたのを
併せて考えると
いろいろと思うところは ある
...and there are a few thoughts that I get.
Perhaps this is near where the key lies.
ひょっとすると
この辺りが鍵なのかもしれない
To the darkness in Nadeko's heart.
千石撫子の心の闇
I asked for her parents' permission, then...
Animation Number 216
I see. So this is Sengoku Nadeko.
なるほど これが千石撫子か
Childish, cute, and disgusting.
子供っぽくて かわいらしくて
気持ち悪い
She seemed like a fake.
なんだか作り物めいていた
It seemed like she was forced to be pretty.
プリティーであることを
強要されているかのようだと思った
She was smiling, but it was somehow awkward.
笑顔は浮かべているが
どこか ぎこちない
She grows her bangs down and tries to not make eye contact, or rather...
前髪を下ろして
人と目を合わさないようにしている
というか もっと言えば
おどおどしているようにも見える
...expounding on that, it seems like she's nervous about something.
What exactly does she fear? What is she afraid of?
彼女は何におびえているのだろう？
何に？
All of the photos are just of her.
（貝木）
１人で写っている写真ばかりですね
I wonder if she never took photos with my daughter.
私の娘とは
写真を撮ったりしなかったのかな
Oh, please don't touch that closet.
（撫子の母）
あ… そのクローゼットには
触らないでください
I asked, and as expected, she was told by Sengoku Nadeko to stay away.
（貝木）
聞いてみると 案の定
千石撫子から
そう言われているとのことだった
It's difficult to describe the emotions I had at this time, so I'll just state the facts.
このときの俺の気持ちを
説明するのは難しい
だから事実だけを記そう
In other words, Sengoku Nadeko's parents, despite the fact that their daughter was missing...
要するに千石撫子の両親は
自分の娘が
行方不明になっているというのに
...kept her room clean and were infatuated only with keeping it the way it was.
部屋をきれいに
元どおりに保つことだけに執心して
And despite the fact that an important clue may be lying within...
ひょっとしたら そこに重要な
手がかりがあるかもしれないのに
...they are doing as they were told by their daughter,
娘の言いなりになって
and didn't even think about opening the closet.
部屋のクローゼットを開けさえ
していないということだった
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 249
Send me a photo of Sengoku Nadeko.
千石撫子の写真を送ってくれ
Unknown Name
What, you don't even know what she looks like?
（戦場ヶ原）
なによ 顔も知らなかったの？
It's a girl I've never met.
（貝木）
会ったこともない女なんでな
You're the one telling me that she's an indirect victim of my doings.
俺の間接的な被害者だなんて
お前が言っているだけだ
よく考えたら
それがホントかどうかも分からん
After much thought, that may or may not be true.
Are you telling me you think I'm deceiving you?
（戦場ヶ原）
私が あなたを
だましているとでも言うの？
I bet you wouldn't want to hear that from me
Animation Number 254
I flipped through a photo album at Sengoku Nadeko's house. She's a cute girl.
千石撫子の家でアルバムを見た
かわいらしい子じゃないか
お前の嫌いそうな
One you probably despise.
No
vehicles
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
You're right.
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（戦場ヶ原）
そうね
Blue Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I hate her type the most.
一番嫌いなタイプよ
Naoetsu elevated bridge 1
Even if this wasn't how we met, I could never be friends with those types.
こんな形で出会っていなくとも
絶対に友達になれないタイプ
Road
narrows
Please
take
another
route
during the
construction
Please
take
another
route
during the
construction
Since you knew her address, have you visited the Sengoku house before?
（貝木）
お前
住所を知っていたということは
千石家を訪ねたことは あるのか？
Unknown Name
Of course I have.
（戦場ヶ原）
もちろん あるわ
One of Araragi-kun's younger sisters was a good friend of Sengoku Nadeko.
阿良々木くんの妹の１人が
千石撫子と
仲の良い友達だったからね
So I managed to go.
そのつながりで何度か
Araragi's younger sister knows of this?
阿良々木の妹は知っているのか？
自分の兄が今陥っている状況を
The condition her big brother is in right now?
Those girls don't know.
Unknown Name
（戦場ヶ原）
あの子たちは知らない
The only people that know are myself, Araragi-kun, Oshino Shinobu, and Hanekawa-san.
知っているのは私と阿良々木くんと
忍野 忍と それから羽川さんだけ
I really wanted to keep it a secret from Hanekawa-san as well, but she figured it out.
本当は羽川さんにも
秘密にしておきたかったんだけれど
Unknown Name
バレちゃった
I'm asking you, who is this Hanekawa?
（貝木）
だから何者なんだ？　羽川
Anyway, with this I was able to get a glimpse of Sengoku Nadeko's family circumstances.
（貝木）
それより俺は これで千石撫子の
家庭事情の片りんのようなものを
知りは したわけだが
Senjougahara, in all honesty, what did you think of Sengoku Nadeko?
戦場ヶ原 実際のところ
お前は千石撫子を どう思った？
Don't think of this as providing information, but more of an informal chat.
情報提供というより
雑談のつもりで言ってくれ
You mentioned earlier you don't like that type of girl... How to put it...
さっき 嫌いなタイプとか
言ってはいたが
何というか…
I want to hear what you think, and an experience you've had with her.
もう少しエピソード交じりの
感想を聞きたい
Hmm? What's wrong?
ん？　どうした？
Actually... I've never met Sengoku Nadeko directly in person.
（戦場ヶ原）
それが… 私は直接
千石撫子に会ったことは ないのよ
What? Is that so?
（貝木）なに？　あっ そうなのか
Yes. We only made one deal over the phone. We had that one conversation.
（戦場ヶ原）
ええ 電話で１度取り引きというか
会話をしたけれど
Even that was after she stopped being a human too.
それだって もう彼女が
人間をやめたあとのことだし
I see. I'm starting to get a grasp of it.
そうか　なんとなく分かってきたよ
This incomprehensible situation that you are facing...
お前の置かれている
訳の分からない状況ってやつが
Stop
I'm surprised you can stay sane through it.
よく正気を保っていられるな お前
Unknown Name
Right.
（戦場ヶ原）
そうね
Well, since you're coming to me for help, I wouldn't be surprised if you've already lost your sanity.
まっ
俺に助けを求めるくらいだから
お前は案外 既に
正気じゃないのかもしれないがな
Unknown Name
Kaiki, I'm telling you, I...
（戦場ヶ原）
貝木 だから私は…
In any case, I'm planning on going to meet Sengoku Nadeko right now.
（貝木）
とりあえず俺は これから
千石撫子に会ってこようと思う
I can meet her at North Shirahebi Shrine, right?
北白蛇神社に行けば会えるんだよな
You're not guaranteed to see her.
（戦場ヶ原）
会えるとは限らないわよ
Araragi-kun said he sees her about once every five visits...
阿良々木くんが
５回に１回くらい会えるのかな
...and each time he sees her, he comes home nearly dead.
その度に殺されかかって
帰ってくるんだけれど
Seems like she can kill him at any time, but is graciously letting him live until the promised day.
いつでも殺せるけれど
とりあえず約束の日までは
生かしてくれているみたい
Rainwater
Araragi isn't heading over today, is he?
（貝木）
阿良々木は今日は来ないな？
I don't want to bump into him inside the shrine grounds.
神社の境内で鉢合わせなんてのは
ごめんだぜ
Unknown Name
He won't be going. Because tonight he's with me... No, wait...
（戦場ヶ原）
行かないわ
だって 今夜は私と… いえ…
Well, if I don't see her, I don't see her. That's fine.
（貝木）
まあ会えなきゃ会えないでも
いいんだ
But I can't begin if I don't see what this place looks like.
とりあえずは現地を見てみないと
話にならないというだけでな
What will you do if you're able to see her?
（戦場ヶ原）
もし会えたら どうするつもり？
Do you already have enough to deceive her?
彼女をだますだけの材料は
もう そろっているの？
Not at all.
（貝木）全然
It's merely to visit and see how she's doing. To put a name to the face...
ただ 一応ご機嫌伺いというか
顔をつないでおく程度のことだ
Besides, this may unexpectedly resolve itself with a good discussion.
それに案外 話し合いで
解決できるかもしれないしな
Unknown Name
I see. I think that's an impossibility, but do your best.
（戦場ヶ原）
そう　無理だと思うけれど
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
頑張って
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 314
Purity in Spirit
Wash your heart and body before visiting the gods
How to
wash
your
hands
How to
wash
your
hands
1. put a ladle
of water on
your left hand
2. next on your
right hand
3. hold a little water in your
left hand, and rinse your
mouth. Cover your mouth
with your
hand when
you spit it
out
4. wash your left
hand again,
since it touched
your mouth
5. finally
wash the
ladle's
handle
with the
water left
This way the next person can do the same easily.
Care for each other!
Here's Nadeko!
（千石）撫子だよ〜！
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 339
I took the time to become a god...
せっかく神様になったのに
...but nobody came up here for their New Year's visit, so it's been boring!
誰も初詣に来てくれなくて
つまんなかったんだ
Old man, can you be my conversation partner?
おじさん
撫子の話し相手になってよ
Ten thousand yen! Ten thousand yen!
いっちまんえん♪
She seems happy.
Animation Number 350
She must be happy.
Thank you, old man!
ありがとうね おじさん
Old man, you're my very first adherent!
おじさんは 撫子の信者 第１号だね
Stop calling me old man. My name is Kaiki Deishu.
おじさんと言うのをやめろ
俺は貝木泥舟(でいしゅう)という
Thinking about it, this was a mistake.
（貝木）
考えてみれば これは失敗だった
Sengoku Nadeko is an indirect victim of the fraud scheme I had going in this town.
千石撫子は 俺がこの町で行った
詐欺の間接的な被害者である
It wouldn't be strange for her to have heard my name. Perhaps from Araragi or the Fire Sisters.
ならば どこかから 阿良々木や
ファイヤーシスターズから
俺の名前を聞いていても
おかしくは ない
That's what I thought.
と思ったのだが
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Kaiki-san!
貝木さん！
Kaiki-san! Kaiki Deishu-san!
貝木さん 貝木泥舟さん
変わった名前だね　よろしく！
That's a strange name! Nice to meet you!
Sorry for calling you an old man!
おじさんなんて言って
ごめんなさい
Yeah, on second look, you're pretty young! Wow, so young!
うん！　よく見たら若いよね
うわ 若！　年下かと思った
I think you're younger than me! I'll just call you young master!
若って呼んじゃう
I'm sure that she heard of my name and knew of it...
（貝木）
きっと 俺の名前を聞いていて
知っているはずだ
But she no longer remembers it.
しかし
それをもう覚えていないのだ
This girl has now forgotten the root of all evil that shoved her into the situation she is in now.
この娘は 自分をこんな状態に
追い込んだ諸悪の根源を
今となっては忘れている
That's what I thought it was. She plainly forgets things that most cannot forget.
そういうことだと思った
忘れられないようなことを
普通に忘れるのだ こいつは
But in return, she forever remembers trivial matters...
そのかわり どうでもいいことを
例えば 子供のころ
...like how the older brother of a friend was nice to her when she was young.
友達のお兄ちゃんに
優しくしてもらったこととかを
いつまでも覚えている
In other words...
つまり 物事の重要性の順序が
It was my understanding
that the order of importance of events within her mind was all jumbled up.
この娘の中では
しっちゃかめっちゃかに
なっているのだと
俺は そう理解した
Right now, I'm eagerly waiting for March to arrive!
撫子はね 今 ３月になるのを
ずっと待ってるんだ
Should I say it? I'm gonna say it!
言っていいのかな？
言っちゃおうかな
When the time comes... Can you believe it?
そのころになったらね なんと撫子
I get to totally kill the person I love!
好きな人を ぶっ殺せるの！
I was asked to wait six months, so I'm here waiting.
半年待ってって頼まれたから
待ってるんだけど
Since I'm a god, I thought that I should listen to requests, after all.
神様だから やっぱり
頼み事は聞かなくちゃって思ってね
The feeling that I can't wait that long grows stronger lately, but I have to wait and bear with it!
待ちきれないって気持ちが
最近は強くなってきてるけど
我慢 我慢
A god has to keep her promises!
神様だから約束は守らなくちゃね
Fake Bank
Ten Thousand Yen
Right. Keeping promises is very important. You could even say it's sublime.
そうだな 約束を守るのは
とても大切なことだ
崇高と言っても いいかもしれない
I shape my replies to the conversation with words I don't mean.
（貝木）
俺は そんな 心にもないことを
言って話題を合わせる
This girl seemed very pitiful, and I could no longer say anything to disapprove of what she said.
この娘が とても哀れに思え
否定するようなことを
言えなくなってしまったのだ
That's how you can think of it.
と思ってくれていい
She frolics at company, or rather a shrine visitor, arriving.
（貝木）
来客… というか参拝客に はしゃぎ
This god, reminiscent of a junior high kid, tries to make good conversation so the visitor has fun.
楽しんでもらおうと
面白い話をしようとする
中学生のような神様が
滑稽で哀れで しょうがなかった
It was nothing but comical and pitiful.
I couldn't help but sympathize.
同情せざるをえなかった
But it's weird. I wonder why nobody comes up here.
でも不思議だな
どうして誰も来てくれないんだろう
The shrine is all new and stuff too.
せっかく神社が新しくなったのに
I thought lots of people would come to visit.
お客さん
いっぱい来てくれると思ったのに
Maybe there isn't enough advertising?
（貝木）
宣伝が足りないんじゃないか？
Or maybe there aren't enough services.
あるいは サービスが足りないとか
Services? Do you mean sexual favors when you say services?
サービス？
サービスって エッチなサービス？
I ignored that.
Animation Number 395
Koyomi-oniichan was really happy when I went topless and wore just bloomers!
（千石）暦(こよみ)おにいちゃんはね
撫子が上半身裸になって
ブルマをはいたら
すっごく喜んでくれたよ
What in the hell is that boy doing?
（貝木）
何をやっているのだ あの男は
Is he a criminal or what?
Animation Number 398
And he was watching so happily when I was writhing about in a school swimsuit...
あと この神社で スクール水着で
撫子がもだえてたのも
...right here in this shrine!
すっごく
うれしそうに見てたんだよ
暦おにいちゃんに喜んでもらえて
撫子も うれしかった
I was so happy that Koyomi-oniichan was pleased by that!
You know, um, you....
なあ えっと…
お前
So you and this... Koyomi-oniichan?
お前は その…
暦おにいちゃんか？
I don't know if Koyomi is his first or last name...
暦というのが名字なのか名前なのか
知らないが
You're in love with Koyomi-oniichan?
お前は暦おにいちゃんのことが
好きなんだな？
Yup! I totally love him!
大好きだよ
That's why I'm going to kill him!
（千石）
だから殺すんだ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Totally kill him!
ぶっ殺すんだ！
I see.
（貝木）そうか
I'm going to kill Koyomi-oniichan's girlfriend what's-her-name...
（千石）
暦おにいちゃんの恋人の
なんとかって人と
...and that young girl slave what's-her-name too!
幼女奴隷の なんとかって人も
一緒に殺すんだ
I thought,
Animation Number 402
"so this girl is just dumb."
"She's stupid."
Animation Number 402
"She's hopelessly short on brainpower."
Pamper to Sengoku Nadeko.
Animation Number 402
She's gonna take it all, naively.
Animation Number 412
Hey, god. If you were able to go back to being human, would you like to?
なあ 神様
お前 人間に戻れるとしたら
戻りたいか？
Nope.
いや
Even if you could be dating Koyomi-oniichan once you turned back to a human?
（貝木）
人間に戻ったら 暦おにいちゃんと
恋人同士になれるとしても？
Yup.
I'm fine with my love not being answered.
撫子はね もう片思いでいいの
If I could keep loving someone forever with no answer...
片思いを ずっと続けられたら
それは両思いよりも
幸せだと思わない？　貝木さん
...don't you think that's happier than loving each other, Kaiki-san?
Unrequited.
Animation Number 412
She died in a traffic accident anyway.
While I know love, I don't know losing it.
Animation Number 412
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
You're right.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（貝木）
そうだな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Koyomi-oniichan has come to this shrine many times already, right?
（貝木）
暦おにいちゃんは 何度も
この神社に来ているのだろう？
それは お前は参拝客…
お客さんには含めていないのか？
You're not including him as a visitor... As company?
Yeah, because Koyomi-oniichan keeps telling me nonsense.
うん　だって暦おにいちゃんは
撫子に訳分かんないことばかり
言うんだもん
よく分かんないから追い返すの
I don't get it, so I just shoo him away.
暦おにいちゃんを殺すのは
３月だって
March is when I get to kill Koyomi-oniichan, so I told him to come back then.
だから そのときに来てって
But he's really annoying, so I often pretend that I'm not here.
あんまり しつこいから
最近は居留守を使うことも多いけど
Nobody else really comes here at all?
（貝木）
ほかには本当に誰も来ないのか？
Are you sure that nobody really came here at all other than Koyomi-oniichan and myself?
暦おにいちゃんと俺以外には
今まで
本当に誰も来たことは ない？
In the beginning, a few people came by, but they all ran away when I went out to greet them.
最初のころ 何人か来たは来たけど
撫子が出ていったら
みんな逃げちゃうの
なんでかな？
Why is that?
逃げなかったのは…
Kaiki-san, you're the first person that didn't run away and the first to put money in the offertory box!
それに さい銭箱に
お金を入れてくれたのは
貝木さんが初めてだよ
So, thanks!
だから ありがとう！
Everyone probably runs away when they see you because you look creepy.
みんなが お前を見て逃げるのは
お前の姿が不気味だからだろう
That hairdo of yours is way too scary.
その髪は怖すぎるぞ
I thought, "now I'm gonna get killed."
Animation Number 436
Creepy? Too scary?
不気味だとか
怖すぎるとか
Nobody's ever said that to me before.
そんなこと言われたの
初めてだな
Everyone always just tells me how cute I am.
みんな撫子のこと
かわいい かわいいってしか
言わないんだもん
For this girl, "cute" is no longer a compliment or something she's happy to hear.
（貝木）
この子にとっては
かわいいというのは
もはや 褒め言葉でも
言われてうれしいことでもないのだ
Or rather, those words have probably limited her from doing many activities.
むしろ その言葉で 多くの行動を
制限されてきたのだろう
So something insulting, basically bad-mouthing, does a full circle and she's happy about it.
だから 侮辱のような
ともすれば 悪口が
１周して うれしかったりするのだ
確かに…
確かにそれならば 人間に戻らず
True enough... True enough that if that's the case...
このまま神様を続けているほうが
この子のためでは あるのだろう
...it's best for her to continue to be a god, rather than return to being human.
After thinking of that, my heart began sink, but even if that's the case...
それを思うと気が重くなりかけたが
しかし たとえそうでも
...I realized it has nothing to do with me.
俺には全然関係がないことに
気付いた
I see. So I'm creepy and too scary, huh?
そっか〜
撫子は不気味で怖すぎるんだ
じゃあ この蛇の髪の毛を
シュシュで縛れば
Then, if I tie up these snake-hairs with a scrunchie...
...will I give off a different image?
ちょっとは イメージが変わるかな
It's getting late, so I'm going to head out soon.
遅くなってきたから
俺は そろそろ帰るぞ
What! Stay and talk a bit more!
もっと おしゃべりしようよ！
貝木さん
Kaiki-san, if you go home, I'll be lonely!
帰っちゃったら
さ〜び〜し〜い！
If you're bored, play with this.
（貝木）
暇なんだったら これで遊んでおけ
What is this? Perhaps cat's cradle?
（千石）
これ 何？
ひょっとして あや取り？
What, you know what it is?
（貝木）
なんだ 知っているのか？
Yeah. It's Nobita-kun's favorite. He's good at cat's cradle, napping, and sharpshooting.
（千石）
うん　のび太君が好きなんだよね
あや取りと居眠りと早撃ちが
のび太くんは得意なんだよ
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
It gives people a peace of mind
knowing how eternal Doraemon is.
Animation Number 472
But I don't know much about cat's cradle...
でも撫子 あや取り
あんまり知らないんだけど
I'll teach you a few patterns.
（貝木）いくつか技を教えてやる
I'll come by again before you've perfected them.
お前が それを極めるまでには
また来てやるさ
Really?
本当？
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（貝木）
本当だ
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Really.
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I've never told a lie.
俺はウソをついたことがない
（千石）ふ〜ん
I honestly said so.
（貝木）
正直に俺は そう言った
And with feigned innocence, or in a scheming way, I continued...
そして白々しく
あるいは腹黒く続けた
After all, I am your first adherent.
何せ俺は
お前の信者 第１号だからな
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）
火憐だぜ！
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
（月火(つきひ)）
月火だよ！
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Love!
（２人）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ！
Together we're the Fire Sisters, but what about the Con Sisters?
（火憐）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ
Eh! If we don't make an
offering you'll
keep being a god?!
じゃあ
たたり合わせば？
（月火）
そんな
呪いの姉妹みたいには
I don't want us to become some sort of malefic siblings.
なりたくないよ
Preview Quiz!
（火憐）
予告編ク〜イズ！
You won't get any
visitors in your current state.
Run-down
Hmm
Quiz!
（月火）
ク〜イズ！
People often say "a skillful toddler", however...
（火憐）
あんよが上手
と言いますが
They do say it a lot.
（月火）
言うかな？　今も
（火憐）
この言葉
ちょっと面白くねえ？
Isn't that amusing? I mean, makes you think about fish, right?
あんよがジョーズって
With this we're done with the cleaning!
ジョーズって魚じゃん！
みたいな
So true!
（月火）
本当だ！
"Even Homer sometimes nods."
（火憐）
ジョーズの手から
水が漏れる
This looks very god-like! It's perfect!
Love Fulfillment
Nadeko will do her best!
Fishy irony!
（月火）
魚なのに！
（火憐）
手も足も出ないとは
このことだぜ
Guess that's what it means to "be at wit's end."
（月火）
このことでは
ないと思うけどね
Yeah... I'm pretty sure it's not.
Next time! Koimonogatari Episode 3!
（２人）
次回「恋物語 第３話
ひたぎエンド 其ノ參(そのさん)」
Next Time
Hitagi End Part 3
Hitagi End, Part 3.
（火憐）
あんよがムカデ
と言うべきだぜ
People should say "a suited toddler".
This is the God
of the Love Spells...
Yeah!
（月火）
言うべきでは
ないと思うけどね
I really don't think they should...